The true enigma was the man who cracked the code.
The Imitation Game is a history, drama, thriller film directed by Morten Tyldum.
Based on the real life story of legendary cryptanalyst Alan Turing, the film portrays the nail-biting race against time by Turing and his brilliant team
of code-breakers at Britain's top-secret Government Code and Cypher School at Bletchley Park, during the darkest days of World War II.
Alan Turing, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Joan Clarke, played by Keira Knightley.
Hugh Alexander, played by Matthew Goode.
Detective Robert Nock, played by Rory Kinnear.
John Cairncross, played by Allen Leech.
Peter Hilton, played by Matthew Beard.
The Imitation Game is a 2014 American biographical thriller film directed by Morten Tyldum and written
by Graham Moore, based on the 1983 biography Alan Turing: The Enigma by Andrew Hodges.
The film's title quotes the name of the game cryptanalyst Alan Turing proposed for answering the question
"Can machines think?", in his 1950 seminal paper "Computing Machinery and Intelligence".
The film stars Benedict Cumberbatch as Turing, who decrypted German
intelligence messages for the British government during World War II.
Keira Knightley, Matthew Goode, Rory Kinnear, Charles Dance,
and Mark Strong appear in supporting roles.
Following its premiere at the Telluride Film Festival on August 29, 2014, The Imitation Game was
released theatrically in the United States by The Weinstein Company on November 14.
It grossed over $233 million worldwide on a $14 million production budget,
making it the highest-grossing independent film of 2014.
The film received critical acclaim but faced significant criticism for its historical
inaccuracies, including depicting several events that had never taken place in real life.
It received eight nominations at the 87th Academy Awards (including
Best Picture), winning for Best Adapted Screenplay.
It also received five nominations at the Golden Globes,
three at the SAG Awards and nine at the BAFTAs.
Cumberbatch and Knightley's highly acclaimed performances were nominated for
Best Actor and Best Supporting Actress respectively at each award.
The film explores themes of england, homophobia,
world war ii, mathematician, genius.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.